Benedict Woo

I am currently a Ngee Ann Polytechnic's School of InfoComm Technology student, pursuing a Diploma in Cybersecurity and Digital Forensics. I also strive to learn and experience more than just academics. I participate actively in NullSec and Overflow Special Interest Group (SIG), where I experience many things outside the typical school curriculum.

Education

- 2020 Present | Ngee Ann Polytechnic, Diploma in Cyber Security and Digital Forensics
- 2016 2019 | School of Science and Technology Singapore, O-Level
- 2010 2015 | Lianhua Primary School, PSLE

Experience

March 2021 - Present

President of NullSec

NullSec is a special interest group that focuses on cybersecurity. As the president, I started various initiatives to help others gain their passion in cybersecurity. In June 2021, the NullSec exco team worked with Cyber Security Agency (CSA) to organise secondary school students' Youth Cyber Exploration Camp. Our NullSec members have a series of monthly workshops covering interesting cybersecurity concepts from Secure Coding with Python to Kali Linux Tools and Commands. Apart from workshops, NullSec also heavily promotes the participants of various Capture-The-Flag (CTF) competitions to put our skills into action. In 2021, I participated many CTFs, including Cyber Defenders Discover Camp, 11th Singapore Cyber Conquest and Gryphons CTF 2021. Moreover, I helped create challenges for some CTFs, namely, the Lag n Crash 2021 CTF competition. Being part of NullSec has helped me further my interest in cybersecurity and explore so much more than just academics.

March 2021 - Present

Vice President of Overflow

Although I major in the cybersecurity field, I also have a great interest in all forms of technology. I also joined the Overflow SIG, where we explore exciting new technology, from fun programming languages like golang to topics such as blockchain technology. Being the Vice President of Overflow, I assist the president in ensuring the smooth running of events. We conduct weekly workshops, where I am in charge of validating the content, and all the workshop materials are completed on time. These workshops cover any topic related to technology. In addition, every term, Overflow conducts a 3-day Bootcamp converting more complex ventures in more detail. In September of 2021, we had a camp on Algorithms and Data Structures where we touched on arrays and mapping structures, as well as tree and sorting algorithms. While these may not all about cybersecurity, it is also essential to understand the technology that we are securing to understand the digital world as a whole better.

June 2018 - June 2019

President of SST Inc.

In secondary school, I was involved in ICT TDP (Talent Development Programme), called SST Inc., which serves as an incubator that nurtures students in running technology start-ups to give back to the community and better our world. As the elected president in 2018, I directed a team of executive committee members in upholding and building up the cooperate culture of SST Inc. I spearheaded various bonding sessions such as INCamp, and managed progress tracking for all start-ups in SST Inc.

In 2019, I was selected for #ProjectSF for showing excellence and exceptional potential in coding and technology. This learning visit to numerous technology companies and prestigious universities provided me with an excellent opportunity and eye-opener to explore my career paths, as well as further my interest in technology-related fields.

Awards & Acknowledgements

- CSIT Diploma Scholarship (AY2020 & AY2021)
- Edusave Certificate of Academic Achievement 2021
- Participated in Gryphons CTF 2021
- Participated in the 11th Singapore Cyber Conquest 2021
- Participated in Cyber Defenders Discover Camp 2021
- Challenge Creator for Lag & Crash 2021
- Participated in STACK the Flags 2020
- Best performance in module Programming I & Programming II
- Most outstanding performance in Level 1 (Semester 1.2, AY2020)
- Director's List for excellent academic performance (Semester 1.2, AY2020)
- CDC-CCC Education Merit Award 2019
- Awarded Bronze for NUS National Olympiad in Informatics 2018
- Awarded Sliver for Australia Informatics Olympiad 2018 (Intermediate Division)

Links

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/benedict-woo-77a483129/

GitHub: https://github.com/benwoo1110

Website: https://benergy10.dev/